

Hugo MORCEAU

Fullstack JavaScript Developer

■ hugo.morceau@gmail.com 🤳 +33 6 58 02 10 65 👂 Barcelona (Spain)

Profil

A dedicated and passionate developer, I have had the opportunity to work with a wide variety of technologies, both Frontend and Backend, with a focus on Web technologies over the last three years. I also have project management experience and am accustomed to working in international environments.

Professional experience

FullStack Web Developer

May 2023 - Present

Extia, Barcelona

Service for Keolis

- Developed and maintained of 60+ websites using React Gatsby and GraphQL, centralizing data via DatoCMS (one instance per site).
- Optimization of performance and user experience for institutional and traffic information sites with tailor-made adaptations.
- Agile methodology work with a focus on accessibility and green IT.

In-House: Development of the Barcelona agency's website

- Revamp of the static website in React with the implementation of a nodeJs Express backend.
- Implementation of a headless CMS (Strapi) for continuous customization and website updates.

Software Engineer / Project Manager

Oct 2017 - Apr 2022

Crédit Mutuel - Euro Information, Paris

In-House (since 2019)

- Management of an international project.
- Drafting of functional and technical specifications in English.
- Supervision of and participation in development and functional testing.

As a Service Provider (2017 to 2019)

Developments in Cobol / Adélia / SQL.

Software Engineer

Jun 2012 - Sep 2016

Hardis Group, Paris

Service for various clients in the fields of banking, insurance, factoring, and securitization

- Developments in Adélia IWS, Visual CL, RPG, SQL.
- Technical and functional analyses.

EDUCATION

Web and Mobile Web Developer

2022

O'Clock

Information Systems Manager

2012 - 2013

CESI, Châteauroux

Developer Analyst CCI de l'indre, Châteauroux 2011 - 2012

Technical Skills

JavaScript, nodeJS, Html/Css

React, Gatsby, NextJS, NestJS

SQL, GraphQL, REST

DatoCMS, Strapi

Docker, Nginx

Linux, AS400

Cobol, RPG4, Adélia IWS

Other skills

Project management

Writing specifications

Technical and functional analysis

Languages

French (native)

English - 910 on TOEIC

Spanish - B2

Links

Portfolio: hugomorceau.com

Linkedin.com/in/hugo-morceau-5b36051b7/

Github.com/HugoMorceau